People who live in the territory of Kyiv,
Люди, которые живут на территории Киева
now the Kyiv region, their ancestors
сейчас Киевской области, ихние предки
lived in Kievan Rus, right?
жили в Киевской Руси, правда?
No,
Нет,
from the city of Khmelnitsky.  Give me a little
из города Хмельниц. Дай-то немно
now, now.  Pogo, wait, wait, let's
сейчас, сейчас. Пого, подожди, подожди,
talk normally.  Yeah, go ahead.  No, I don't
поговорим нормально. Да, давай. Не, я не
want to fight.  I am from the city of Khmelnitsky.   Where are
хочу ссориться. Я из города Хмельницкий.
you from?   Where are
Вы откуда?
you from?  I am from the city of Khmelnitsky.
А вы откуда? Я из города Хмельницкий. Вы
What city in Russia are you from?  We are from Russia, I
из какого города России? Мы с России, я
see.  What city is it?  To Narinmar.
вижу. А город какой? На Наринмар.
Narinmar.  Oh, I know.  Is this Yamal Nenetsky
Наринмар. О, знаю. Это Ямал Нененицкий
or not Khanty?  No, no, this is
этот или не ханте? Не, нет, это
non-Nitsky
неницский
autonomous.  Nenets Autonomous Region.  Here you go, Nenets.
автономно. Ненецский автоном. Во, ненце.
Okay then.  OK.  I see.  Yes, you see,
Так, о'кей. О'кей. Я вижу. Да, видишь,
yes, yes.  Listen, guys, I'm really
да, да. Слушай, пацаны, мне очень
interested in talking to you, because
интересно с вами поговорить, потому что
usually Russians are indamurts,
обычно русские попадаются индамурты,
like you're Germans,
типа вы немцы,
right?  Yes, yes, yes.  By the way, I saw a
да? Дадада, да. Я видел, кстати,
program about Naymar.  There was
передачу типа про Наймар. Там один ээ
this one, uh, traveler, like, he was traveling,
этот путешественник, типа, он ездил,
filming, like, just like that.  Well, usually, like, what's
снимал, типа, как раз. Ну, обычно, типа,
it called?  Lyadov.  Lyadov, I think, right?   Yes,
как это как его? Лядов. Лядов вроде, да?
yes.  Yes, Lyadov, like, he was
Дадада. Да, Лядов, типа вот вот он же
like in Narinmar and like he came
типа в Наринмаре и типа приезжал
to Elminovsky.  Yes, yes.  And so I remember
и на Эльминовском. Да, да. И вот я помню
his video, yes.  It's just that usually
типа его видео, да. Просто обычно
Russians there, you know, tell me
русские там, знаешь, мне рассказывают
that there in the north
там вот что там на севере чуть ли не
there are almost some kind of savages living, yes, like,
какие-то там дикари живут, да, как бы
it's normal, like, well, not normal, there are
вот нормально, типа, ну не нормально,
some, yes, [ __ ], there are also normal
есть такие, да, [__] есть и нормальные
people, like.  No, well, look,
люди, как бы. Не, ну так смотри, просто
they just say, it’s clear that in the Moscow
они говорят, ясно, что и в Московской
region there is someone who lives in a village and
области есть кто-то, кто в селе живёт,
keeps a cow, right?  How is he different from
держит корову, да? Чем он отличается от
someone who keeps reindeer?  Nothing, really.
того, кто держит оленей? Правда, ничем.
Here.  But they somehow extol that these people
Вот. Но они как-то превозносят, что вот
live there in the far north, I know,
эти там на крайнем севере живут, знаю,
there are some kind of wild tribes there.  Here.  And
там какие-то дикие типа племена. Вот. А
here they are in Moscow, in short, everything is straight.  No,
они тут в Москве, короче, все прямо. Не,
no, no, I'll tell you, I'll tell you, there is such a
не, не, я я тебе я тебе скажу, есть
thing, there is such a thing, there is.  Yes, well, it seems
такое, есть такое, есть. Да, ну, как бы
like in cities and villages, mostly
в основном как бы городах, деревнях
healthier people live.  There are wild tribes,
более здравые живут. Дикие племена есть,
right?  Where they still pump, where they don’t know
да? Там где ещё ещё качуют, где не знают
civilization at all.  There are such peoples.
вообще цивилизации. Есть такие народы.
No, it’s as if civilizations
Не, есть как если как бы цивилизации
know, but they are, you know, so tough, they are
знают, но они знаеш жёсткие такие, они
afraid of us in general.  Although we are also
опасаются у нас вообще. Хотя мы тоже
Germans, they are afraid of us.  Do you know your own
немцы, но они нас опасаются. Вы свой
German language?
нецкий типа язык знаете?
Well, I know a little, and he knows a little too.  I
Ну я немного знаю, он тоже немного. Я
also kind of understood a little, yes, a little,
как бы тоже немного, да, немного понял,
yes.  I basically
да. Я в основном как бы на русском
speak Russian and that's it.  Yeah, got it.  Well, because
говорю и всё. Угу, понял. Ну потому что
in our village, everyone
как бы в деревне у нас как бы вот все на
speaks Russian, yes, and they kind of
русском говорят, да, и как бы такое вот
understand things like that.  Well, there are those who can
понял. Ну есть, которые умеют прямо
communicate directly in German, but I
вообще общаются вот на немецком, но я
kind of got used to communicating in Russian
как бы привык как бы на русском общаться
since childhood and understood.  Well, you are already like
уже детство и понял. Ну а вы уже как
Russians, right?
русские, да?
Worse, worse, worse, worse,
Похлеще, похлещее, похлеще, похлещее,
worse.  All.  Yes, in this you have been
похлеще. Всё. Да, в этом вас
Russified.  Understood.  Yes, it's interesting.
русифицировали. Понял. Да, интересно.
Here.  And look, uh, Germans, there are
Вот. А смотри, ээ, немцы, вот к немца, к
some peoples that are even closer to the Germans,
немцам какие народы ещё более близкие,
so that I
чтобы я вот родственные народы у вас у
don’t think that the
не
Khanty are related to you.  No, no, Khanty and Mansi are
Ханты. Не, не, Ханты и Манси - это
different, they are different.
другое, это другое.
No, not Khanty, yes, close.  Khanty,
Нене, не ханты, да, приближенный. Ханты,
Khanty.  No, in my opinion, the Khanty and Manti are
Ханты. Не, по-моему, Ханты и Манти они
more like Hungarians.
они боле они к венграмму типа ближе.
No, no, no.  Khanty, Enets, Ganasan.
Нет, нет, нет. Ханты, энцы, ганасаны.
Komi is
Коми
not Komi, it is definitely not related to
не коми это точно не родственный
Germans.  Komi, Komi, look.  Quiet, quiet,
немцам. Коми коми смотри. Тихо, тихо,
let me, let me tell you.  What do we have in common with Komi?
дай, дай скажу. У нас коми что похоже? У
We have one dwelling, we have one
нас жилище одно, у нас одежда одна с
piece of clothing.  We ride on the same sleigh.  The sleigh is the
комий. Мы ездим на одних же санях. Сани
same.  We also harness a team of reindeer.   They
такие же. Также упряжка олени запрягаем.
don't travel either, just like us.
Также не ездят, как и мы.
By the way, my name is Andrey.  What is your
Меня, кстати, Андрей зовут. Вас как
name?  Kirill.  Roma.  Kirill and Roma.  So.
зовут? Кирилл. Рома. Кирилл и Рома. Так.
Yes.
Угу.
Well, they are related people, you don’t know
То так родственный народ вы не знаете
who is who more, well, they are related people to the
кто кто более ну там родственный народ к
Germans.  Yes,
немцам. Да
we are Germans, right?  There are Enets.  No.
мы немцы, да? Энцы есть. Нет.
Ensyganasany Khanty-Mansi.  Not Khanty.  I
Энсыганасаны ханты манси. Не ханты. Я
know.  Khanty-Mansi are from the same language
знаю. Ханты Манси - это из той языковой
group as the Hungarians.  It's like
группы, что и венгры. Типа
they live a little bit in the wrong place.  No no no.
они немножко не тут живут. Нене не.
Hante Mansi to us.  There is Hungarian food there.
Ханте Манси к нам. Там венгерская едит.
No, no, no.  Hante Mansi to us.  No.
Нет, нет, нет. Ханте Манси к нам. Нет.
Oh, well, I'll dial right now.  I'm
А, ну сейчас я прямо наберу. Мне
curious because Germans, yeah, I don't
интересно, потому что немцы, да, я не
meet Germans that often, yeah, so
так часто встречаю немцев, да, поэтому
what is it?  No, look, you are the
что это как его? Нет, смотри, ну вот ты
first adequate person who
первый адекватный человек, который с
communicates normally with Ukrainian flags
украинскими флагами общается нормально
.  Well, yes, yes.  Otherwise, this, uh,
вообще. Ну да, да. А то на нас этот, э,
whoever it was, what did they call us?
кто там, как назвали?
Tingiskangi.  And you, you really are the
Тингисканги. И вы вы реально вы реально
first Germans who speak to me normally
первые немцы, кто со мной нормально
.  Really.  But we are not serious,
говорит. Реально. А так не мы серьёзно,
we communicate normally.  Well, it’s just that there were
мы общаться нормально. Ну просто вот на
attacks on us, well, from Ukraine
нас вот, ну с Украины как бы вот наезды
, but I said to one guy
были, но как бы я говорю вот один чувак
: “Well, you guys,
такой: "А во вы а
go ahead.”  I say: "You say they
идите". Я говорю: "Говоришь вы тебя
called you something or something?"
что-то както назвали или что на?"
Yes.  Ali will come.  I don't know.  What did he
Угу. Али приедет. Я не знаю. Он что тебе
tell you?  He said, "Coming soon."  Ah,
сказал-то? Он сказал: "Сейчас подо". А,
you see, right?  They write, they write, like in
видишь, да? Пишет, пишут, что типа в
Wikipedia they write that among the Germans there are
Википедии пишут, что в среди немцев есть
some clans, yes, clans of
некоторые роды, да, роды происхождения
Khanty, Komiziryan,
Хантыйского, Комизырянского,
Selpuk origin, right?  So it turns out that
Сельпукского, да? То есть получается у
you got mixed up somewhere, right?  Maybe
вас где-то смешивались, да? Может быть,
so?  That's what I'm telling you.  Well, you see,
да? Вот я же тебе и говорю. Ну, видишь,
I have, you see, I have a board, even
у меня, видишь, у меня борда-то даже
look, will you come over?  No, we'll get there, redheads.   My
смотри, подъедешь? Нет, рыжие мы доедем.
mother told me that
Это мне мама говорила то, что с это
we had a mixture with these zaryans.  Does mom know?
заряными у нас смесь была. А мама знает?
Mom knows who the mixture was with.  No, no,
Мама знает, с кем была смесь. Да не, не,
it’s like pure nonsense.  My mother, my mother is
это как бы чистый несц. Ма мать моя
pure.  The father is a pure Nenet.  But we have
чистая. Отец чистый нец. Но у нас где-то
ore somewhere far away.  Wait.  Yes, mom, in short,
далеко в руду. Подожди. Да мама, короче,
mom is a pure non-pure child, dad is a pure non-pure
мама чистый не чистояненка, отец чистый
child, but the son has a red beard.  And my mother
нец, но у у сына рыжая борода. И мама
was like: “Well, that was someone in the family a long time ago.
такая: "Ну, это кто-то давно в роду
”
был".
No, no, seriously, like this one there
Да не, не, серьёзно, как бы этот там
somewhere is some kind of product, she said
где- это какой-то продт, она говорила
that this one, what's his name, mom mom
то, что этот, как его, мамка
, yes, mom crossed.  Look,
мамка, да, мамка пересекла. Смотри,
look, you're not hiding my mother.
смотри, ты мою мать не скрывляешь.
Look, my grandmother's mother is a
Смотри, у моей у моей бабушки мать
comic, and I am a non-com.  So I understand.  My
комий, а я нец. Так понял. Вот у меня
grandfather is Russian, purely Russian.
вообще дедушка русский, чисто русский. У
My father's grandfather is Russian.  It
меня у отца дедушка русский. У тебя
turns out that you are a Russian Nenets and a Komi all
получается ты русский ненец и коми всё
in one bottle.  Yes, yes.  Understood.   Yes,
типа в одном флаконе. Дадада. Понял.
yes.
Дадада.
Interesting.  Well, as you see, in my
Интересно. Ну как бы у меня, видишь, в
passport it is not written that, well,
паспорте это нец как бы написано то, что
essentially, it is clean.  What I'm saying is
ну по сути как бы чистый. Этот я говорю
that there are branches there and then there aren't any, look
то что там веточ-то идёт-то и нет смотри
there, there won't be any.  The Germans don't have a
там там же не будет. У у немцев нет
portable one.  Here is
переносницы. Вот
the transfer.  Do you know where?  Where is
здесь перенос. Знаешь где? Где
the bridge of the nose?  This is the carrier.  Here is
переносица? Вот эта переносница. Вот
the bridge of the nose.  Okay, I have this
здесь переносица. Так, а у меня вот
.  And Roma doesn't have any at all.  Come on, Roma,
есть. А у Ромы нету вообще. А ну, Рома,
turn sideways.  Turn sideways, Roma.
повернись боком. Повернись боком, Рома.
They're not crazy, are they?  Yes.  Well, it
Нема не соманые же. Угу. Ну вы
turns out that, look, the Germans do not
получается, смотри, немцы они не
belong to the Turkic peoples.  Like, it's a
относятся к тюрским народам. Типа это
different branch, like.  No no.
другая ветка, типа. Нет, нет.
Samadian group.  Samadian.
Самадийская группа. Самадийская.
Samadian.  Samadian, yes.  Exactly,
Самадийская. Самадийская, да. Точно,
exactly.  Yes.  Samadian.  Yes.  Interesting.
точно. Да. Самадийц. Угу. Интересно.
Listen, are you in Russia or
А слушай, ты что сейчас в России или на
Ukraine now?  Now in Ukraine.  What did I forget in
Украине? Сейчас в Украине. Что я забыл в
Russia?  What about me, I would probably be like you
России? Я что, я бы, наверное, как вы,
if I were in Russia.  His eye was
если бы был бы в России. У него глаз
twitching.
дёргался.
What city are you in?
А в каком городе находишься?
City City Khmelnitsky.
Город Город Хмельницкий.
Yes, I understand.  But Khmelnitsky isn't being
Да, понял. А Хмельницкий-то ещё не
bombed yet.  What is this?
бомбят. Это что?
Khmelnitsky is your city.  Well, the fact that
Хмельницкий-то город твой. Ну то что
Khmelnitsky is
Хмельницкий
not being bombed has already been bombed.  There was bombing a couple of days
не бомбят ещё бомбили. Вот пару дней
ago.
назад бомбили.
missiles were flying at civilians, victims,
прилетали ракеты мирным
dead civilians, not a
жерт погибших мирных жителей да ни
single soldier, three dead civilians, at
одного военного трёхе погибших мирных по
civilian targets, civilians, that's
мирным объектам мирные жители
why
поэтому поэтому
among
между
themselves, that's why everyone
собойму поэтому да вот вас все и
calls you names because, damn, and you're from Russia
обзывают потому что блин а вы из России
because you're the one shooting at us, that's
потому что это вы по нам стреляете вот
why everyone doesn't like you, so we're
поэтому вас все и не любят так вот нам
like, you're
типа вот Вот вы
pigs to you.
свиньи вам.
If there is a draft, I will also go to
Если если призыв будет, я тоже пойду на
war.  Why
войну. Зачем
me?  This is our homeland.  We defend with No,
я? Это наша родина. Мы защищаем с Нет,
look, do you know what my position is,
смотри, у меня знаешь какая позиция,
Kirill?  If you come to me Wait, stop, stop,
Кирилл? Если ко мне Подожди, стоп, стоп,
stop.  You Germans, something... Wait, stop.
стоп. Вас, немцев что-то Подожди, стоп.
You Germans have a population of about 40,000, I
Ваш вас, немцев что-то 40.000 населения,
think, yes, if I'm not mistaken, right?  50
по-моему, да, если я не ошибаюсь, да? 50
50,000 population, right?  So you are a
50.000 населения, да? То есть вы
dying people, and you say that
вымирающий народ, и ты говоришь, что
if this is Why dying?  On the contrary,
если это Почему вымирающий? Наоборот,
on the contrary, it grew, grew, grew.  He grew up.
наоборот вырос, вырос, вырос. Он вырос.
And there were 40,000, now there are 50. No, there were
А было 40.000 стало 50. Да нет, было
less.  You were multiplying.
меньше. Было вы расплодились.
We are growing.  We are growing, of course.  Look,
Мы растём. Растём, конечно. Смотри,
now you see, the planet is becoming overpopulated
сейчас, видишь, идёт перенаселение
.  And now you see, the warriors
планеты. И сейчас вот видишь, воины
have started to liberate part of the planet and the
начали, чтобы освободить часть планеты и
fight for resources is like this
борьба за ресурсом вот такая
.  No, but my point of view is that I will
вот. Нет, но моё мой взгляд то, что я я
go anyway, if if if they
пойду всё равно, если если если меня
neglect me, I will go.  Ki, tell us about the fight
брезут, я пойду. Ки, расскажи про борьбу
for the planet's resources.  This is what
за ресурсы планеты. Вот это меня
interests me.
интересует.
This is Roma.  Roma.  Roma, yes.  This is Roma, yes.
Это Рома. Рома. Рома, да. Это Рома, да.
It’s like this, that
Это как его вот то, что как бы
now, well, like, for oil, for
сейчас, ну как бы за нефть там, за
something else, for gas, I’m howling like that.  So
что-то ещё, за газ вою так. Так
what is overpopulation?
перенаселение что?
He is fighting for the transfer of the population to Russia.
Воюет за переноси вот в Россииселение.
Yes, look, now the
Это да, смотри, сейчас народу сейчас
environment is suffering for the people, environmentalists are beating them up a lot.
экология страдает, экологи очень бьют.
Well, as you can see, people,
Ну, как бы видишь, люди,
construction is very, what is it called, well, it’s
строительство-то очень это, как его, ну,
going on, it’s going on in
как бы идёт, идёт
full swing.  I don't think you
этим полный. Я думаю, у тебя канала
have a channel.  Look, in short, how can you
никакого нету. Смотрите, короче, вот как
not stop him, Rom, wait, do you
его не стоп, Ром, подожди, у тебя канал
have some kind of channel?  No, there is a channel.
есть какой-нибудь? Нет, есть канал.
Glaciers.  What kind of channel do you have?  The channel
Ледники. Что за канал у тебя? Канал
is called Andrey Popoch.
Андрей Попоч называется.
How?  Glaciers,
Как? Ледники,
as
как
per attempts.  Andrey Popyt.  Oh, I'll send it to you in the
по попыт. Андрей Попыт. О, скину вам в
chat, as Popyt writes in Russian.  Yes,
чатик, как пишет Попыт на русском. Да,
I just sent her the message she wrote.  Priest.  Yes,
вон я скинул, как она пишет. Попик. Да,
I have a funny last name about a priest.  Let's
смешная у меня фамилия про попик. Давай
laugh.  And you Yes, yes, yes, come on, Roma, let's
посмеёмся. А вы Да, да, да, давай, Рома,
laugh, come on.  No, guys, you're
смеёмся, давай. Не, пацаны, вы
cool.  Let's do a like like this
прикольные. Давайте сделайте вот так
.  Let's like each other.  How is it there?
лайк. Сделаем друг другу лайк. Как там?
Oh look, we kicked it.   Can
О, смотри, мы напинали.
you imagine what he writes there?   Do
Прикинь, там что пишет-то?
you want to go too?
тоже хочешь пойти?
Saving the planet.  Yes, yes, yes.
Спасают планету. Да, да, да.
This is what betsukha is.  Not real.  Show,
Это вот это бецуха. Не реально. Покажи,
show the betsukha to
покажи бецуху
yourself.  In short, your biceps are
себе. Вот это, короче, у тебя бицуха,
like Kiryukha's head.
как у Кирюхи голова.
Kiryukha, show me your biceps.  Adam
Кирюха, а ты свою бицуху покажи. Адам
was Adam was a Nenets.  Adam was definitely
был Адам был ненец. Адам точно был
a little bit.  Come on, come on, throw it, throw it
немножко. Ну-ка, ну-ка, кидай,
.  But
кидай. А на
not this.  Come on, come on, let's fight
не это. Давай, давай, давай битвы ещё
again.  Come on, come on, make a face.  Come on,
раз. Давай, давай, делай лицо. Давай,
make a face like this.  Let's.
сделай лицо, как вот было. Давай.
This is a powder, make your face as it was.  You have
Это поро сделай лицо, как было. У тебя
a lot of chemova,
оченьческомова,
come on.
давай.
No, Roma, you really, damn, I'm talking from the
Не, Рома, ты реально, блин, я говорю с
point of view of artistry, like, Roma,
точки зрения артистизма, типа, Рома, у
you have, in short, such a range of facial expressions,
тебя, короче, та такая гамма мимики,
like, it's really possible.  I also like to, like,
типа, реально можно. Я тоже люблю, типа,
make different faces.  52. Yes, hello,
разные рожи строить. 52. Да, здравствуй,
Saint Petersburg.
Санкт-Петербург.
In short, Roman, look, I’ll tell you right now
Короче, Роман, смотри, я тебе вот сейчас
.  If you don’t start your own channel,
скажу. Если ты не заведёшь свой канал,
yes, on YouTube and don’t start posting this stuff there
да, в Ютубе и не будешь там гнать вот
.  Yes, I wanted him, how many times have I
это. Да, я хотел ему сколько раз я тебе
told you.  Look, you'll get there, in short,
говорю. Смотри, ты попадёшь, короче, ты
when you get to the next world, yes,
когда попадёшь на тот свет, да, придёт
Apostle Peter will come and tell you:
апостол Петро, тебе скажет:
"And how did you leave here, in short, damn, you do
"А как пошёл отсюда, короче, блин, ты
n't have your channel? I,
твой канал не
you see, look, the peoples, you
У меня, видишь, смотри, народности как
know, believe that, well, there are
бы, знаешь, верят то, что, ну, там
some idols, some gods. I don't believe
какие-то идолы, боги какие-то. Я не верю
in all this. I'll just die and die. Nothing will
во всё это. Я просто умру и умру. Ничего
happen anymore. Na I just have to
не будет больше. На Я просто должен
pass on my family, like, and I will
передать своё семье, как бы, и я буду
live for another. No, no, everything is correct.
жить другому уже. Не, не, всё правильно.
You will pass on your seed, and
Ты своё семя передашь, а Кирюха в
when Kiryukha goes to Ukraine, like, yes, to
Украине когда пойдёт, типа, да, на
war, like,
войну, типа,
I don't know, he still sings Ukraine.
я не знаю, он поёт ещё Украина. При мне
Give me the dog in my presence.
дай пёс.
Oh, how far away it all is. Because we are also
Ой, как всё далеко. Потому что мы ещё и
on the channel, like. And how old are you? And
на канале как. А ты сколько? А ты
how old are you, or have you been there since childhood? I've
сколько или с детства там вообще? 42
been living there for 42 years from birth.
года живу от рождения.
And where are I from? From Khmelnytsky. I
А родом откуда? Из Хмельнико. Я прямо в
was born right in Khmelynsky.
Хмелинском родился.
And 42  years. And in
А 42 года. А
general, who was Ukraine 42 years
вообще 42 года Украина кем
ago?
была назад?
So, a young politician woke up in Roma. In
Так, в Роме проснулся юный политик. В
Kirill. In Kirill.
Кирилле. В Кирилле.
Come on, Kirill, let's talk.
Давай, Кирилл, поговорим.
Who was Ukraine 42 years ago? Ukraine
42 года назад кем была Украина? Украина
42 years ago was the Ukrainian Soviet
42 года назад была украинское советское
Socialist Republic now. Kiryukha in general Kiryukha,
социали сейчас. Кирюха вообще Кирюха,
listen to me importantly.
слушай меня важно.
Ukraine 42 years ago was the Ukrainian
Украина 42 года назад была украинской
Soviet Socialist Republic.
Советской Социалистической Республикой.
Yeah. And before that, who was it? Yes. The Ukrainian
Угу. А до этого кем было? Да. Украинской
Republic. Before the Soviet Union. Before
республикой. До Советского Союза. До
that, it was the Ukrainian Ukrainian
этого было украинской украинской
People's Republic.
народной республикой была.
No, before the Soviet Union. Before the Soviet
Нет, до Советского Союза. До Советского
Union, there was the Ukrainian People's
Союза была Украинская народная
Republic. Hurray, look, imagine, Kirill, do you
республика. Ур, смотри, прикинь, Кирилл,
know which one? And where did Kievan Rus
знаешь какая? А вот Киевская Русь где
originate? These are our ancestors, you know?
зародилась? Это наши предки, знаешь?
Look, come on, come on, wait. Stop, stop, stop, stop
Смори, давай, давай, подожди. Стоп,
, wait, Kiryukha,
стоп, стоп, стоп, подожди, Кирюха,
look. Attention,
смотри. Внимание,
in fact, now, wait. No, an
по сути, сейчас, подожди. Нет, в Кирюхе
inner historian woke up in Kiryukha. I like
проснулся внутренний историк. Я люблю
this, you know,  Here, Kiryukha, look,
такое, знаешь, вот, Кирюха, смотри,
Bodya, Bodya, Bodya, look.
Бодя, Бодя, Бодя, смотри.
Come on,
Давай,
Roma, come on, tell me, tell me, in short, for
Рома, ну скажи, скажи мне, короче, за
your subscribers. Come on, come on, come on.
твоих подписчиков. Давай, давай, давай.
For you, for you, sign up, come on. Kiryukha,
За ва за вас подпивай, давай. Кирюха,
tell me, what two words does the
скажи, из каких двух слов состоит слово
word Kievan Rus consist of?
словосочетание Киевская Русь?
Rus, what two words? Rus, Kievan
Русь вы каких двух слов? Русь Киевская
Rus. That's right, right? Adjective
Русь. Правильно, да? Прилагательная
Kievan noun Rus. Question.
Киевская существительная Русь. Вопрос.
Attention, question. Why is the first word
Внимание, вопрос. Почему первое слово
Kievan?
стоит киевское?
Why? Because it was the capital of
Почему? Потому что это была столица
Rus. The capital of
Руси.
Rus. Yes. Rus. The capital of Rus.
Столица Руси. Да. Русь. Столица Руси.
Where did the Russians live? It was Rus, not
Где жили русские? Это была Русь, а не
Russia. Rus, Russians didn't live there. There were no Russians
Россия. Рус там русские не жили. Русских
then. Look,
тогда ещё не было. Смотри,
damn it. In short, Roma, I respect you. You
блин. Короче, Рома, я тебе респект. Ты
really are smarter than Kirill. Are you
реально ты реально умнее Кирилла. Ты
at least like an artist, like funny? Yeah.
хоть типа артисти типа весёлый? Да.
No, I'll tell you, Roma, you're a really wise
Не, я скажу, Рома, ты реально мудрый
person.  This Kirill is a little bit,
человек. Вот этот Кирилл немножко,
in short. Well, you're smart. Look, Kirill. And
короче. Ну а ты умный. Смотри, Кирилл. А
he's a normal guy. He's quiet, don't
э он нормальный парень. Он тихо не
say it outright. Kirill, look. Yeah
говори прямо. Кирилл, смотри.
. Kievan Rus was centered in
Угу. Киевская Русь была с центром в
Kyiv, right? Yeah. Yes. People who
Киеве, правда? Угу. Да. Люди, которые
lived in Kiev Look, the Germans
жили в Киевско Вот смотри, немцы,
who lived 1,000 years ago, yes, uh, on the
которые жили 1.000 лет назад, да, ээ, на
territory where Narinmar is, and
территории, где Наринмар, и сейчас там
their ancestors live there now, right? Those people
же живут ихние предки, да? Те люди,
who Yeah, look, people who live
которые Да, смотри, люди, которые живут
on the territory of Kyiv now the Kyiv
на территории Киева сейчас Киевской
region, their ancestors lived in Kievan
области, ихние предки жили в Киевской
Rus, right?
Руси, правда?
Oh,
Оо,
no, sorry, subscribers, I'm
нет, извините, подписчики, я сейчас
a little Kirill, where? Let's do it this way. People
немного Кирилл, где? Давай так. Люди,
who now live in Kyiv.
которые сейчас живут в Киеве.
Kirill, Kirill, come on. They lived in the
Кирилл, Кирилл, давай. Они жили на
north. They lived in the north.
севере. Они жили на севере.
In more detail they came with
Детальнее они пришли с с монголоидной
this [ __ ] race. So we Sayan, well, northern
этой расой. Так мы Саян, ну северный
peoples essentially there, well, [ __ ]
народы по сути там, ну монголоидные
races.  Let's do it again. 1 thousand years
рассы. Давай так ещё раз. 1тыся лет
ago in Kyiv, on the territory of the
назад в Киевской вот на территории
modern Kyiv-Zhytomyr region,
современной Киевской Житомирской области
there the Ukrainians all descended from the Russians.
там украинцы же все пошли от русских.
So our Russians captured the northern
Так русские наши захватили северные
peoples. Except for the Chukchi, there were only
народы. Кроме кроме Чук чукчи одни были
those who were this
те, которые этот
unconquered people.
непокорённый народ.
But the Germans and everyone else there were covered with vodka
А вот немцев и всех там покрыли водкой
. Then there was an exchange. Then I
всех. Потом обмен был. Потом я знаю
even know how the carcasses were taken out there, what's it called
даже, как туши вывозили там этот, как
, they write here, the head is bigger, so it
его, тут пишут у голова больше, поэтому
thinks better. Yes, really, really,
соображает лучше. Да, реально, реально,
I'm telling you, I
я тебе говорю, я
really, look, Roma, although he is a funny
реально, смотри, Рома, хоть он и смешной
character, such a thing
как бы персонаж такой вещ больше сейчас
will become bigger now. Come on, but Roma has more than
стану. Ну-ка, но у Ромы больше, чем у
Kirill.
Кирилла.
He has less. He has less. No, he
У него меньше. У него меньше. Не, у него
really has more. His IQ
реально больше. Чуточку сейчас на IQ
has gone up a little now. Nuro, Roma, I'll tell you this
поднялся. Нуро, Рома, я тебе вот что
, Roma, you need to start your own
скажу, Рома, тебе нужно завести свой
YouTube channel. I'm telling you,
YouTube канал. Я тебе говорю, вот
you're really smart. Yes, I wanted to, I didn't
реально ты умный. Да я хотел, я не я не
figure it out, I wanted a stream on Tansk
разобрался, хотел стриму по Танск
Blitz, I didn't figure it out in ObS.
Блиц, не разобрался в этом в ОбS.
Yeah, look, let me sign. I hope I'll
Да, смотри, давай подпишусь. Я надеюсь
sign, Kirill. Look, here's the question.
подпишусь, Кирилл. Смотри, вопрос такой.
Let me ask you again. Look. People who
Ещё раз давай. Смотри. Люди, которые
lived
жили
, uh, modern Ukrainians, yeah, where did
вот, э, современные украинцы, да, где
their ancestors live? Here are people who
жили ихние предки? Вот люди, которые
live in the Kyiv region, in the village where
живут в Киевской области, в селе, где
their ancestors lived 1,000 years ago? In
жили ихние предки 1.000 лет назад? На
Rus'. In Rus'. That is, there, there in the
Руси. На Руси. То есть там же, там же в
territory of Kyiv, yeah, they
территории Киева, да,
lived in Rus', right? So it turns out that, uh,
на Руси жили, да? То получается, что ээ
modern Ukrainians, yeah, it was their
украинцы современные, да, это ихние
ancestors who lived in Rus'.
предки жили на Руси.
No. And Kievan is, uh, it's like it's
Нет. А киевская это по, э, как бы
subdivided into the fact that Ukrainians lived there
подразделяется то, что там жили ээ
. Well, how can I
украинцы. Ну, как бы вообще, как
say, [ __ ] hell, that Kievan.
сказать-то, [__] что Киевская.
Kievan, yeah. You see how there were
Киевская, да. Ты видишь, как его были
nationalities, there was this, like Well, there is
народности была этот, как Ну, народности
no Kievan nationality. There is no nationality. All the
киевской же нету. Народности нету. Все
peoples were in the
народы были в
USSR, they had different languages. This
СССР, у них разные языки были. Это из
even Poland came from Rus', all sorts of
Руси пошло даже там Польша, там всякие
things there, Polish. Well, like similar
дела, поляские. Ну, как бы похожие
consonant languages ​​there. Kirill God.
созвучные языки там. Кирилл Бога.
He went, you know what? The ancestors,
Он пошёл, знаешь что? Предки вот,
you know, divided everything, and now we,
знаешь, разделили всё, а сейчас мы,
[ __ ], in my brain to create a creative
ёпты, в моём мозгу создать созидательное
society there was no country
общество не было стран
one different
один разные
languages ​​all help each other. there was no way for
языки все другу помогают. не было, чтобы
this one, who is above all of us and for
этот, который над всеми нами и чтобы
this, what is it called, uh, how can I tell you, it's
это, как его, ээ, как тебе сказать, это
they who always dot us all and what
же они же всегда нас всех всех дот и то,
I want to say,
что я хочу сказать,
this is stupid now such a speech,
этот туплю сейчас такую речь
[ __ ]. Well, look, I would now, you know
ебану. Ну, смотри, я бы сейчас, знаешь,
what I want to say?
что я хочу сказать?
[music]
[музыка]
that we should, those who are with us, well, they
что мы должны, те, кто у нас, ну, вот
extract all the resources, we should really
добывают все ресурсы, вот вот реально им
pay them money to get these
платить деньги, чтобы получать эти
resources and like in certain
ресурсы и как бы в определённых
areas, so that there would be our own, what is it called,
областях, чтобы были вот свои этот, как
well, [ __ ] him, he will be the main one, but he
его, ну, хуй с ним, главный будет, но он
shouldn't
же не должен
receive, he should, like, like
получать, он же должен как бы, как и
everyone else, receive money, but he would
все, получать деньги, но как бы он
just be in control of this and
просто будет контролем заниматься этим и
everything.
всё.
And it seems to me that this is the creative
И мне кажется, это содеязательное
society of the future. And what is happening now,
общество будущего. А то, что сейчас
some kind of
какой-то
intercontinental
вообще создали межконтинентальные
missiles were created, so that each other, so that some would
ракеты, чтоб друг друга, чтобы одни
assign to others, others would assign back. There
посваят другим, другие посваят обратно.
will be no peace, or what? This is
Мира-то не будет, что ли? Это же
madness.
сумасшествие.
[music] It's
[музыка]
crazy. And they also
С ума сойти.
created several steps to
Ещё и создали несколько шагов, чтобы
get to this
дойти до этой
button. These are
кнопки. Этому
people. Be
это люди.
serious. Don't say that. [ __ ], do
Серьёзно говори. Не говори так. Ёпты, у
you really have this, Kiryukha?
тебя что на самом деле так есть, Кирюха?
What is it? You see, people, this is necessary.
Что есть-то? Это надо, видишь, люди.
Okay, in short, Roma, look, stop.
Ладно, короче, Рома, смотри, стопай.
Roma, calm down. I've spoken out.
Рома, успокойся. выговорился.
Oh, yes, I've spoken out. It's become easier.
Ой, да я выговорился. Легче стало.
Look, let's do it this way. We've already listened to everything a little
Смотри, давай так. Мы уже немножко всё
, listen to me. Listen. Let's do it
послушай, послушай меня. Послушай. Давай
this way. Let's do it
так. Давай сде
Wait. For the finale. So. You're a
Подожди. Для для финалочки. Так. Ты
really cool dude, right? For
реально крутой челик, да? За
creative society, in short. Kiryukhin
созидательное общество, короче. Кирюхинь
there lightly so with leganets, in short, for a
там легонько так с леганца, короче, за
creative society. We do not give. No,
созидательное общество. Мы не даём. Не,
no, this is my durgan at all. We are smoking to
не, это мой дурган вообще. Куришь мы
be. Well, you are far away. Well
быть. Ну ты далеко находишься. Ну ты
, come on, come on, in short, subscribe
давай, давайте, короче, подписывайтесь
to Andrey,
на Андрея,
like. Oh,
лайкосик. Ой,
damn, this is a new channel. Subscribe to it
блин, це новий канал. Підпишись на ньго
right now. Set a call to
прямо зараз. Постав дзвоник, щоб
receive all notifications. We will be in touch.
отримати усі сповіщення. Будем на звзку.